Oliver Bathurst | Full Stack Developer

linkedin.com/in/oliverbathurst
oliverbathurst@outlook.com
github.com/OliverMBathurst
olivermbathurst.github.io

Professional Profile

A highly initiative-taking and diligent individual, who has completed their degree in Computer Science from the University of Reading, graduating with highest honours and an academic award. Currently I am working within the Healthcare sector and have extensive experience in full-stack development in the Risk Management and Consultancy sectors, building enterprise software. I am currently using the following tech stack: C#, React, TypeScript, SQL, Azure, .NET Core/.NET Framework.

Skills

• C# • .NET Core • .NET Framework • Full Stack Development

SQL
React
TypeScript
JavaScript

Azure
Visual Studio
Git
Unit testing

Agile
NUnit/MSTest

Experience

Sept 2020 to Present, NHS Improvement

Address: Wellington House, 133-155 Waterloo Road

- Aug 2023 to Present, Senior Developer
- Oct 2021 to Aug 2023, Developer
- Sept 2020 to Oct 2021, Support Developer
- Main duties/experience:
 - Created a search indexer as an Azure WebJob to facilitate searching across NHS core products
 - Full stack development of the NHS Insights Platform primarily, using React, C#, .NET Core
 - Pioneered a multi-threaded email sending solution to process application invitations 90%+ faster than the previous method
 - Created new micro-service applications from the ground-up to automate processes such as email sending
 - Creating full-stack features using TS/JS/HTML/CSS/C#/SQL/EF
 - Refactoring legacy code, converting to TS

Jan 2020 to Sept 2020, CGI - C# Software Engineer

Address: 250 Brook Dr, Reading RG2 6UA

- Main duties/experience:
 - Regularly attending daily meetings/stand-ups
 - Updating important documentation and processes
 - Updating the internal wiki

Jun 2018 to Dec 2019, Sword GRC - C# Software Developer (Full-Stack Developer)

Address: 1 Grenfell Road, Maidenhead SL6 1HN

- Main duties/experience:
 - Independently creating features and bug fixes for their flagship product Active Risk Manager in an Agile fashion
 - Conferring with colleagues about best practices and UI design decisions
 - Engaging in full-stack development, from Typescript to C#

Sept 2017 to Jun 2018, University of Reading - Year 3 Course Representative

- Main duties/experience:
 - Consulting with students and staff, setting up effective communication channels to engage with student queries

Regularly attending meetings with staff, highlighting student concerns

Sept 2017 to Oct 2017, FutureLearn - Java/Android Mentor

- Main duties/experience:
 - Helping users create their first Android app/game in Java
 - Answering programming questions from people around the globe
 - Helping fix and optimise Java/Android code

Education

2015 to 2018, University of Reading - BSc. (Hons) Computer Science

- Graduated with First Class Honours (78%)
- Studied a variety of different modules within computer science, including computer architecture, operating systems, object-oriented programming/programming, algorithms, databases, information security, and cryptography

2013 to 2015, City of Oxford College - BTEC Level 3 IT Practitioners

D*D*D* (Highest Honours)

2010 to 2013, Lord Williams' School - GCSEs

• 8 A*- C (Including Maths and English)

Honours & Awards

Jul 2018, Hockney Prize - University of Reading

 Prize for being the 'Best Computer Science Student' - achieving the highest mark in Computer Science

Certifications

April 2021, Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

No expiry date

Volunteer Experience

in2scienceUK

Address: 10 Queen St PI, London EC4R 1BE

May 2019, Placement Interviewer

Main duties:

- Helping to allocate STEM placements to A-level students.
- Advising and encouraging prospective university students, giving computer science specific instruction where appropriate
- Imparting knowledge of further study and informing students of the choices they have

July 2018, Workshop Instructor

Main duties:

- Assisting and encouraging aspiring university hopefuls in programming
- Running programming workshops, teaching rudimentary Java/C# and fundamentals/paradigms of OOP and procedural programming